- Vibe coding lets you build apps
-Vibe 編碼可讓您構建可以
that solve your work problems, but why do we call it that?
解決工作問題的應用程序，但為什麼我們這麼稱為？
Well, it's a fun way for you to build something helpful
好吧，這是一種有趣的方法，可以在不需要編
without needing to code.
碼的情況下構建一些有用的東西。
All you have to do is know the vibe
您所要做的就是了解您想
of what you want to achieve.
要實現什麼的氛圍。
Okay, there's a little more to it than that,
好吧，除此之外還有一點
and that's what I'm here to show you.
，這就是我在這裡向你展示的東西。
See, a year ago, when these models had come out,
看，一年前這些模特出現時，
I wanted to see if I could make a childhood game of mine.
我想看看我是否能製作自己的童年遊戲
And I didn't know the limits of what was possible,
而且我不知道什麼可能的限制，
but for three days I persevered through all sorts of errors,
但是在三天裡，我堅持地通過各種錯誤，到了最
and by the end of it, somehow that game was made.
後，以某種方式的遊戲就成了。
Now, fast-forward a year from then.
現在，從那時之後一年來快速前進。
Today, if I just give the model one screenshot,
今天，如果我只給模型一張屏幕截圖，
it can make the entire game for me.
它可以為我製作整個遊戲。
It's wild how fast these things are moving.
這些東西移動的速度很瘋狂。
And so how do you bring that to your work?
那麼你如何把它帶到你的工作中？
To give you an idea,
為了給您一個想法，我
we'll practice building a few apps together.
們將一起練習建置幾個應用程序。
Here's a sneak preview of the three apps we'll build.
以下是我們將構建的三個應用程序的潛在預覽。
The first app I like to call The Tiebreaker.
我喜歡稱為「決勝者」的第一個應用程序。
This is an app that I built
這是我專門為幫助做出棘手
specifically to help make tricky decisions.
的決定而構建的應用程序。
You'll customize it so that it understands
您將自定義它，以便它了解
your preferred approach to decision-making.
您喜歡的決策方法。
For example, do you like to compare
例如，您喜歡並排比較
two options side by side,
兩個選項，
or are you someone who likes to go deep
還是您喜歡深入研究成本效
on a cost-benefit analysis?
益分析的人？
This app will help you analyze your options
此應用程序將幫助您分析選項，
so that you feel good about your decisions.
以便您對自己的決定感到良好。
The second app is a Marketing Materials Generator.
第二個應用程序是營銷材料生成器。
Need creative for an upcoming launch,
在即將
or a promotion, or an announcement?
推出、促銷活動或公告中需要創意嗎？
With this app, you can create ads,
使用此應用程序，您可以創建廣告，
stickers, banners, posters,
貼紙，橫幅，海報
and other visuals to help you sell your product.
和其他視覺效果，以幫助您出售產品。
This app speeds up the creative process
此應用程序加快創意過程，
so you can create custom assets
因此您可以為每個受
for every segment of your audience.
眾部分創建自定義資產。
The third app we'll build
我們將構建的第三個應用程序
is what I like to call an interactive dashboard.
是我喜歡稱為交互式儀表板的應用程序。
With this app, you'll be able to visualize your data fast.
使用此應用程序，您將能夠快速可視化數據。
No more static graphs or charts
不再需要每天刷
you have to refresh every day.
新靜態圖形或圖表。
This app keeps your data visualizations fresh
此應用程序可讓您的數據視覺化保持新
so that anyone can get answers when they need them.
鮮，以便任何人都可以在需要時獲得答案。
Feeling excited?
感到興奮嗎？
Before we dive in, I want to introduce you
在我們深入研究之前，我想
to a new AI tool, Google AI Studio.
向您介紹一個新的 AI 工具，即 Google AI 工作室。
At Google, I lead an incredible team
在 Google，我領導了一個不可思議
of engineers, designers, and product managers
的工程師、設計師和產品經理團隊，他們
who help craft the experience in AI Studio
在發
or capability that is released so that people like you
布新的 AI 模型或功能時協助打造 AI Studio 的體驗，讓您這樣的人們了
understand how to make the most of it.
解如何充分利用它。我
We'll use AI Studio to build our apps.
們將使用 AI 工作室來構建我們的應用程序。
To access it, go to aistudio.google.com.
要訪問它，請訪問 aistudio.google.com。
Once you get there, you'll notice the page
到達到此處後，您會注意到該頁面與
is a bit different from Gemini,
Gemini 有點不同，
so let's take a second to walk through the tool.
所以讓我們花一點時間瀏覽該工具。
AI Studio starts on a home screen with a few main options.
AI 工作室在主屏幕上啟動，並具有幾個主要選項。
The first is chat,
第一個是聊天，
where you'll write your prompts to get an output.
您將在其中編寫提示以獲取輸出。
On the right side,
在右側，
you'll see settings to modify your outputs.
您會看到修改輸出的設置。
You can select from all of the newest models
您可以從所有最新模型中選取
to complete your task,
以完成任務、新
add system instructions that the model processes
增模型處理
before using your prompt to provide output,
的系統指示，然後再使用提示提供輸出、
adjust the temperature, and more.
調整溫度等。
Next, we have build,
接下來，我們將建置，
which is where we'll spend our time in this course.
這是我們將在這個課程中度過時間的地方。
When you select the build function to create an app,
當您選擇構建功能來創建應用程序時，
you'll see a text box at the top.
您將在頂部看到一個文本框。
This is where I'll prompt Gemini models to vibe code.
這就是我將提示 Gemini 模型進行振動代碼的地方。
It works just like the other AI tools,
它與其他 AI 工具一樣工作，
but this time we'll direct it to build the three apps.
但這次我們將指導它構建三個應用程序。
To vibe code your own app, you can either write a prompt
要對您自己的應用程序進行 vibe 編碼，您可以編寫提示
or use one of the samples below.
或使用以下範例之一。
As we build each app, pay close attention to a few things.
在我們構建每個應用程序時，請密切注意一些事情。
Notice the natural flow of conversation
注意您與
between you and AI Studio.
AI 工作室之間的自然對話流程。
You'll iterate by using plain language
您將使用簡單的語言來迭
to describe what you need to refine requirements,
代來描述您需要改進需求、
to test the output, and to improve the result.
測試輸出以及改善結果的內容。
Next, pay attention to how specific
接下來，請注意您需要
you'll need to get with your feedback.
對您的反饋進行具體意見。
That's because vague descriptions yield generic results.
這是因為模糊的描述會產生一般的結果。
The more precise you are when describing what you need,
您在描述所需的內容時越準確，
the more likely the app will match what you're looking for.
應用程序就越可能匹配您正在尋找的內容。
You are the director, user, and tester of your app,
您是應用程序的總監，用戶和測試人員，
and now you can use AI as your developer tool.
現在您可以將 AI 用作開發人員工具。
Finally, the coolest part.
最後，最酷的部分。
See how fast you'll move
瞭解您將從想法轉
from an idea to a working prototype.
移到工作原型的速度。
In the time it takes to have a chat over coffee,
在喝咖啡聊天所需的時間裡，
you can go from, "I wish there was a tool for this,"
您可以從「我希望有一個工具來做到這個工具」轉
to, "Here's my custom solution."
到「這是我的自定義解決方案」。
So let me show you how.
因此，讓我向您展示如何。